itg.be 2018-09-03

# 

The Institute of Tropical Medicine (ITM) takes your privacy and the confidentiality of your personal information very seriously. That is why we do everything we can to comply with privacy legislation such as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and take the necessary security measures.

Using this privacy statement we wish to inform you about the way we deal with your data and which rights you may exercise yourself.

## For what purposes does ITM process your personal data?

ITM only processes personal data about you when it is for a legitimate purpose, such as:

  * In the context of a service you request (e.g. making an appointment and creating a medical file during a medical consultation, creating a student file if you are following a training course, inclusion in a file for newsletters, etc.)
  * A legal obligation to process or share data (e.g. in the context of public health, authorities, tax certificates, etc.)
  * When you give us explicit permission for a particular processing (e.g. for participation in a scientific study)
  * When there is a well-considered public or legitimate interest

## How long does ITM store your data?

In principle, we do not keep your personal data any longer than necessary in order to be able to execute and complete the requested services correctly. It is possible that there are legal minimum time limits for keeping records (e.g. 30 years for a medical file, 20 years for clinical studies, 7 years for tax certificates or invoices, etc.).

In some cases, certain data are analysed and stored in an aggregated way (e.g. research into outbreaks of epidemics, evolutions in vaccinations, participations in and satisfaction with training courses, visitor numbers). This information is then no longer linked to your identity.

## Will your personal data be transferred?

Your personal data will only be transferred to third parties if this is part of a legitimate or considered and justified transfer, or if you give permission for it to be passed on. We therefore always ensure that we only transfer your data to organisations and for activities where this is allowed.

For scientific research it is also possible that pseudonymised (i.e. with a code and without mentioning your name or other directly identifiable information) or anonymized data about you are used and transferred to researchers. Such research is always approved in advance by an Ethics Committee and a processing of pseudonymised medical data is always performed under the responsibility of a physician.

## Are your data stored in a secure way?

ITM makes every effort to treat your data as confidentially and safely as possible. We take the necessary security measures to limit the risk of unauthorised access, loss or disclosure (e.g. by hacking). To this end ITM implements a strict privacy policy for its employees and all employees sign a statement of confidentiality.

## What are your rights?

You are always entitled to know what data about you we process, why and to whom we pass it on. You may also inspect this data and have it corrected where necessary. In some cases you may also have your personal data removed (the “right to be forgotten").  
If you believe that we incorrectly handle your data, you may also contact the Belgian Privacy Commission.

## Additional questions or comments?

Please contact [informatieveiligheid@itg.be](mailto:informatieveiligheid@itg.be) or phone +32 (0)3 247 07 43.
